<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction_Tutorial on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/introduction_tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction_Tutorial on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/introduction_tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Brand Monitoring Vendors with Other Operational Awareness Approaches</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-brand_monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-brand_monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Operational Awareness is one of the most important aspects a firm must perform. However, most firms don&amp;rsquo;t have an office directly responsible for this work. Instead, a subset of this work, Brand Monitoring, is part of the Marketing department, which might include a more general reputation and crisis management office, if the firm is large enough. Below, explores this field, as well as tools and approaches to improve efficacy of results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminology Useful for NLP</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-intro_terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-intro_terminology/</guid>
      <description>NLP allows for both theoretical and practical study of language. Below are a few of aspects of study, as well as terminology, that is frequently used within the field. Because of the interdisciplinary nature of computational linguistics, the terms come from linguistics, computer science, and mathematics.
Semiotics - a philosophical theory covering the relationship between signs and the things they reference.
Phonetic and Phonological Knowledge - Phonetics is the study of language at the level of sounds while phonology is the study of the combination of sounds into organized units of speech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining Sample Size for AI Models</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-sample_size_calc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-sample_size_calc/</guid>
      <description>We are going to dive into the deep disturbing world of sample size in AI. This work is RARELY done as part of AI solutions. There are comparatively few research papers on this topic, and the approaches they offer tend to be specific to the underlying problem addressed in the paper. However, the simple fact that it is poorly understood gives great understanding to the world of AI, which is why I describe it as &amp;lsquo;disturbing&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpaCy Internals</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-spacy_internals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-spacy_internals/</guid>
      <description>I think there is some confusion about the different components - I&amp;rsquo;ll try to clarify:
The tokenizer does not produce vectors. It&amp;rsquo;s just a component that segments texts into tokens. In spaCy, it&amp;rsquo;s rule-based and not trainable, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t have anything to do with vectors. It looks at whitespace and punctuation to determine which are the unique tokens in a sentence.
An nlp model in spaCy can have predefined (static) word vectors that are accessible on the Token level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network Basics: Linear Regression with PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-neuralnet_pytorch_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-neuralnet_pytorch_intro/</guid>
      <description>In just a few short years, PyTorch took the crown for most popular deep learning framework. Its concise and straightforward API allows for custom changes to popular networks and layers. While some of the descriptions may some foreign to mathematicians, the concepts are familiar to anyone with a little experience in machine learning. This post will walk the user from a simple linear regression to an (overkill) neural network model, with thousands of parameters, which provides a good base for future learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PySpark Refresher Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_bigdata_pyspark-refresher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_bigdata_pyspark-refresher/</guid>
      <description>Spark is the primier BigData tool for data science, and PySpark supports a natural move from the local machine to cluster computing. In fact, you can use PySpark on your local machine in standalone mode just as you would on a cluster. In this post, we provide a refresher for those working on legacy or other systems, and want to quickly transition back to Spark.
Environment When using the pyspark-shell, the spark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with XML Data Using Python</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_datastore-xml_elementtree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_datastore-xml_elementtree/</guid>
      <description>Together with JSON, the XML format is the most popular structure for data on the web. It is not only used for data storage, but also for websites, in the form of HTML. XML was seen as the ubiquitous data format, but with the ascent of Javascript, JSON became more popular for web applications. Still, XML is an effective format, and learning to parse and work with it is necessary for anyone who works with a variety of data sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Numpy and Pandas</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_ds-intro_numpy_pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_ds-intro_numpy_pandas/</guid>
      <description>Numpy and Pandas are the basic data science tools in the Python environment. Having a good understanding of their capabilities and how they process data is imperative to writing optimal code. This post provides an introductory overview and a refresher for those who might come back to the libraries after taking a break. The end of the post explains external interfaces for increasing code execution and performing more sophisticated matrix operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Matrices and Tensors in PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-matrix_tensor_operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-matrix_tensor_operations/</guid>
      <description>The Artificial Intelligence field is moving from single-function libraries to frameworks for building different network models. TensorFlow was one of the first, and has strong production capabilities, such as process optimizations. However, its syntax is unintuitive, and the library has a reputation for being difficult for testing new models. This led to many organizations adopting PyTorch, with underlying Numpy, for designing network models. This post describes the basic data structures for working with Matrices and Tensors in PyTorch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
