<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tag3 on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/tags/tag3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tag3 on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/tags/tag3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Background of NLP with Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-history_nlp_deep_learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-history_nlp_deep_learn/</guid>
      <description>The automated linguistic annotation of natural languages kept linguists and computer scientists hard at work for many decades. This work focused on the syntax of language as well as basic understanding and includes part-of-speech, named entity categorization, and syntatic dependency. Language meta-data tagging became much more accurate with the introduction of neural network and deep learning models. Because pairing meta-data with more powerful models is sure to allow for an explosion of new applications, it is important to understand the developments that allowed for the creation of this technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototyping an Interactive Frontend with Vue</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_prototype-creating_frontend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_prototype-creating_frontend/</guid>
      <description>Assumes you are comfortable with HTML, CSS, JS. This will cover creating SPAs with webpack and Vue basics. This will not cover mobile or advanced Vue. Improvements will make frontend development a more imperative programming approach as compared to the typical declarative methods found in more basic work.
Introduction Once you understand the basics of browser languages, such as HTML, CSS, and JS, then you quickly desire to have more interactive elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Difficult (Abstract) Subjects to Customers</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-explain_metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-explain_metrics/</guid>
      <description>Stakeholders want to understand what you are selling and how your approach is different. However, the level of detail they want varies greatly among your different customers. A simple whitepaper can be useful enough, in most situations. But, occaisionally, a layman will want to know exactly what you are doing and will not be content until you very succinctly explain it to them. This post will explain two methods for approaching such obstacles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to Students: Math is the Basis for Competitive Edge in Every Field</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_math-competitive_edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_math-competitive_edge/</guid>
      <description>Math is the greatest tool humans have for solving problems. However, it is incredibly expensive to get the experience of using it in the real-world. This is magnified by most teachers, and many university professors, not having any experience applying math anyplace other than academic contexts. This post shows the author&amp;rsquo;s trying experiences with learning maths in school, as well as the excitement of applying them to solve actual industry problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Math from the Ground-Up</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog-logic_for_math/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog-logic_for_math/</guid>
      <description>After completing basic high school mathematics, one might think that math stands on its own. To understand and know that 1+1=2 is obvious. But math can go much deeper. In fact, we can build new concepts from math as well as build a math, itself. This is important because it effects how we think about other subjects, and is especially useful in helping us think about language and abstract concepts, such as in programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication Workflows with Hugo, Jupyter, and Friends</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog-hugo_site_process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog-hugo_site_process/</guid>
      <description>Static Site Generators are quite popular replacements for traditional server-based methods of delivering HTML. One of the most popular is Hugo because of its compilation speed. Combining Hugo with Jupyter notebooks, and other tools, can provide for a speedy workflow for pushing your ideas to the web, books (online or pdf), and more. This post will discuss why you may want to do this and provides tools for doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog-intro_latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog-intro_latex/</guid>
      <description>LaTeX is the document preparation and typesetting system used for scientific publications. LaTeX is based on the idea that &amp;lsquo;it is better to leave document design to document designers&amp;rsquo;, so the user can focus on the content. It requires a greater technical understanding than typical simple note-taking systems; however, because it is incredibly descriptive and produces aesthetically-appealing output, it is becoming more popular. This post provides a reference to configuration and syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Data Scientist&#39;s Guide to Modern Java(8&#43;) and the JVM</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_programming_java-modern_java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_programming_java-modern_java/</guid>
      <description>Most data scientists avoid the Java Virtual Machine (JVM) like the plague. The features that make developers and data engineers so productive as a team, such as access modifiers and powerful IDEs, feel slow, old, and cumbersome to individuals interacting with data and prototyping new algorithms. However, the JVM and its supporting system matured to an indominatble force since its inception. It is ubiquitous in the most popular open-source projects; espectially in Big Data and distributed systems, such as Hadoop and Kafka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Command Line with Fish Shell</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_cmdln-linux_fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_cmdln-linux_fish/</guid>
      <description>The Linux terminal (typically implemented with the Bourne Again Shell Script, BASH) can be intimidating for beginners and annoying for experienced programmers. But, it is a necessity for most users of Linux; and, in many situations, it can also be a huge productivity enhancer over graphical interfaces.
Fish is a commandline tool that is a great complement to BASH. It is highly configureable and provides nice features such as syntax coloring and TAB command completion, out-of-the-box.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>