<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pytorch on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/tags/pytorch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pytorch on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/tags/pytorch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Computer Vision Using PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-pytorch_computervision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-pytorch_computervision/</guid>
      <description>The deep learning movement began by applying neural networks to image classification. PyTorch became a leading framework for work in this field. This post provides a cheatsheet to some of the basic methods used for computer vision, using PyTorch.
Configuration This is a typical environment setup. Seed the Random Number Generator for all devices (both CPU and CUDA) using manual_seed() so that work can be reproduced. Computations are deterministic only on your specific problem, platform, and PyTorch release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network Basics: Linear Regression with PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-neuralnet_pytorch_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-neuralnet_pytorch_intro/</guid>
      <description>In just a few short years, PyTorch took the crown for most popular deep learning framework. Its concise and straightforward API allows for custom changes to popular networks and layers. While some of the descriptions may some foreign to mathematicians, the concepts are familiar to anyone with a little experience in machine learning. This post will walk the user from a simple linear regression to an (overkill) neural network model, with thousands of parameters, which provides a good base for future learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Matrices and Tensors in PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-matrix_tensor_operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-matrix_tensor_operations/</guid>
      <description>The Artificial Intelligence field is moving from single-function libraries to frameworks for building different network models. TensorFlow was one of the first, and has strong production capabilities, such as process optimizations. However, its syntax is unintuitive, and the library has a reputation for being difficult for testing new models. This led to many organizations adopting PyTorch, with underlying Numpy, for designing network models. This post describes the basic data structures for working with Matrices and Tensors in PyTorch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
