<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business_and_Leadership on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/business_and_leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business_and_Leadership on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/business_and_leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Brand Monitoring Vendors with Other Operational Awareness Approaches</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-brand_monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-brand_monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Operational Awareness is one of the most important aspects a firm must perform. However, most firms don&amp;rsquo;t have an office directly responsible for this work. Instead, a subset of this work, Brand Monitoring, is part of the Marketing department, which might include a more general reputation and crisis management office, if the firm is large enough. Below, explores this field, as well as tools and approaches to improve efficacy of results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Levels of Customer Explanations for Data Science</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-customer_explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-customer_explanation/</guid>
      <description>Every customer is different. That seems obvious until they begin to ask you specific questions about your work - or they don&amp;rsquo;t ask anything at all. It is good to have a framework for providing information: starting general and moving to more specific. Note that at no time are you at the math or calculation level. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen that go well.
Solution level: What you&amp;rsquo;re doing Nothing special here, just input and output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powerpoint Usage: Commercial vs Government Firms</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-communication/</guid>
      <description>Powerpoint is becoming a de-facto form of communication both within and between organizations. This has both pros and cons, but the important thing to emphasize, when you can, is that it is just a tool. As soon as slides become a sacred cow, then you&amp;rsquo;re no longer delivering value. You&amp;rsquo;re just pushing propaganda.
Commercial
can be a useful tool provide talking points a way to start a discussion with the customer leads to key concepts that customer should take away fewer presentations, but similar pitch, supports personal engagement will definitely have a few important numbers, that will be discussed not the place to make promises / commits; that is during contract negotiation and final delivery Government</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Slack&#39; Form of Communication - From A Business Size Perspective</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_pm-tech_communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_pm-tech_communication/</guid>
      <description>A colleague of mine has put-off using Slack for a while. She&amp;rsquo;s totally committed to Skype for Business, which I&amp;rsquo;m a little revolted by. When I described Slack to her, &amp;lsquo;Instead of separate conversations, you have a continuing discussion or narrative with people. You often end using it as a Knowledge Base&amp;rsquo;. Her response to that, &amp;lsquo;so I can&amp;rsquo;t use it for the things that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go in writing &amp;ndash; got it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public vs Private Sector Employment</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-hire_for_govt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-hire_for_govt/</guid>
      <description>Comparing offers between the federal government and private sector can be very difficult. It is more akin to choosing between an academic career than it is a choice with another commercial employer. Because of the benefits the government offers, it is very much an apples and oranges comparison.
Here are three huge benefits of working with the government:
Retirement - occaisionally, some very large, older firms (insurance or banking) will have a pension system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
