<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nlp on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/tags/nlp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nlp on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/tags/nlp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing Natural Language with Python and Friends</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-intro_spacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-intro_spacy/</guid>
      <description>Python is a typical language chosen for Data Science work, and its strengths with strings make it especially useful for working with natural language. While the nltk library opened-up this work for python users, the newer spacy improves upon processing power by implementing Cython code. Tests display its power in production when compared with more traditional approaches, such as with Stanford&amp;rsquo;s CoreNLP. This post is an outline of examples from the spacy coursework and examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Background of NLP with Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-history_nlp_deep_learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-history_nlp_deep_learn/</guid>
      <description>The automated linguistic annotation of natural languages kept linguists and computer scientists hard at work for many decades. This work focused on the syntax of language as well as basic understanding and includes part-of-speech, named entity categorization, and syntatic dependency. Language meta-data tagging became much more accurate with the introduction of neural network and deep learning models. Because pairing meta-data with more powerful models is sure to allow for an explosion of new applications, it is important to understand the developments that allowed for the creation of this technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Difficult (Abstract) Subjects to Customers</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-explain_metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-explain_metrics/</guid>
      <description>Stakeholders want to understand what you are selling and how your approach is different. However, the level of detail they want varies greatly among your different customers. A simple whitepaper can be useful enough, in most situations. But, occaisionally, a layman will want to know exactly what you are doing and will not be content until you very succinctly explain it to them. This post will explain two methods for approaching such obstacles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Math from the Ground-Up</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog-logic_for_math/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog-logic_for_math/</guid>
      <description>After completing basic high school mathematics, one might think that math stands on its own. To understand and know that 1+1=2 is obvious. But math can go much deeper. In fact, we can build new concepts from math as well as build a math, itself. This is important because it effects how we think about other subjects, and is especially useful in helping us think about language and abstract concepts, such as in programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Textual Problems with Regular Expressions</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-regular_expressions_workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-regular_expressions_workflow/</guid>
      <description>Regular Expressions provide an important foundation for learning systems. They are useful for quick and direct approaches to solving problems without creating mounds of training data, nor the infrastructure for deploying a model. While they are a common programming technique, and simple enough to employ, they tend to be used so infrequently that you must re-learn them each time you wish to apply. This post summarizes the basic regex syntax, strategies, and workflow in hopes it will decrease the time needed to implement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>