<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Comparison on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/comparison/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Comparison on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/comparison/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Powerpoint Usage: Commercial vs Government Firms</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_biz-communication/</guid>
      <description>Powerpoint is becoming a de-facto form of communication both within and between organizations. This has both pros and cons, but the important thing to emphasize, when you can, is that it is just a tool. As soon as slides become a sacred cow, then you&amp;rsquo;re no longer delivering value. You&amp;rsquo;re just pushing propaganda.
Commercial
can be a useful tool provide talking points a way to start a discussion with the customer leads to key concepts that customer should take away fewer presentations, but similar pitch, supports personal engagement will definitely have a few important numbers, that will be discussed not the place to make promises / commits; that is during contract negotiation and final delivery Government</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Stories vs Data Stories</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_pm-user_stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_pm-user_stories/</guid>
      <description>Agile is used to remove uncertainty from projects, so that the features for development are fairly clear, at least for the current iteration. However, producing an analytics application creates many more tasks because it is focused on data. To remove uncertainty from these data tasks, and the overall project, we keep it separate from development. This ensures that we: i) understand the data, ii) have a clear methodology for addressing problems using the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Slack&#39; Form of Communication - From A Business Size Perspective</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_pm-tech_communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_pm-tech_communication/</guid>
      <description>A colleague of mine has put-off using Slack for a while. She&amp;rsquo;s totally committed to Skype for Business, which I&amp;rsquo;m a little revolted by. When I described Slack to her, &amp;lsquo;Instead of separate conversations, you have a continuing discussion or narrative with people. You often end using it as a Knowledge Base&amp;rsquo;. Her response to that, &amp;lsquo;so I can&amp;rsquo;t use it for the things that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go in writing &amp;ndash; got it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The R and Pandas Dataframe</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_ds-dataframe_r_and_pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_ds-dataframe_r_and_pandas/</guid>
      <description>Although Pandas uses the Dataframe as its primary data structure, just as R does, the Pandas syntax and underlying fundamentals can be disorienting for R users. This post will describe some basic comparisons and inconsistencies between the two languages. It will also provide some examples of very non-intuitive solutions to common problems.
Introduction In the Datascience R versus Pandas debate, it is really an apples and oranges comparison. R is a domain specific language in the field of statistics, analytics, and data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Insecurities of the &#39;Great Men&#39;</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_history-greatman_insecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_history-greatman_insecurity/</guid>
      <description>While it may be tough to find the true nature of people, past their outward appearance, it can provide insight into all people, and to yourself. The &amp;lsquo;Great Man&amp;rsquo; theory that leaders are born and not made came about in the 19th century when British aristocrats attained powerful positions through nepotism. It was primarily concerned with explaining leaders such Walpole, Wellington, and Caesar. Much of what is learned in history is their propoganda - getting the reality is much more difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
