<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>markdown on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/tags/markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in markdown on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication Workflows with Hugo, Jupyter, and Friends</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog-hugo_site_process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog-hugo_site_process/</guid>
      <description>Static Site Generators are quite popular replacements for traditional server-based methods of delivering HTML. One of the most popular is Hugo because of its compilation speed. Combining Hugo with Jupyter notebooks, and other tools, can provide for a speedy workflow for pushing your ideas to the web, books (online or pdf), and more. This post will discuss why you may want to do this and provides tools for doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formatting a Markdown Post</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_test-my_first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_test-my_first_post/</guid>
      <description>Cupiditate voluptas sunt velit. Accusantium aliquid expedita excepturi quis laborum autem. Quas occaecati et atque est repellat dolores. Laudantium in molestiae consequatur voluptate ipsa.
Nulla quia non qui sed. Voluptatem et enim nesciunt sunt pariatur. Libero eius excepturi voluptatibus reprehenderit. Facere enim neque dolorem sed ullam non. Dolor sit molestias repellendus.
Awesome-1 Facilis maiores doloribus similique sint quaerat reiciendis quia. Autem nemo voluptas rerum. Eos odio aut omnis. Adipisci voluptas nihil autem recusandae.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>