<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Math on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Math on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Background of NLP with Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-history_nlp_deep_learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_nlp-history_nlp_deep_learn/</guid>
      <description>The automated linguistic annotation of natural languages kept linguists and computer scientists hard at work for many decades. This work focused on the syntax of language as well as basic understanding and includes part-of-speech, named entity categorization, and syntatic dependency. Language meta-data tagging became much more accurate with the introduction of neural network and deep learning models. Because pairing meta-data with more powerful models is sure to allow for an explosion of new applications, it is important to understand the developments that allowed for the creation of this technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to Students: Math is the Basis for Competitive Edge in Every Field</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_math-competitive_edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_math-competitive_edge/</guid>
      <description>Math is the greatest tool humans have for solving problems. However, it is incredibly expensive to get the experience of using it in the real-world. This is magnified by most teachers, and many university professors, not having any experience applying math anyplace other than academic contexts. This post shows the author&amp;rsquo;s trying experiences with learning maths in school, as well as the excitement of applying them to solve actual industry problems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>