<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tag1 on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/tags/tag1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tag1 on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/tags/tag1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating an Initial Training Sample into a Project</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_math-reuse_tng_sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_math-reuse_tng_sample/</guid>
      <description>During a data science project, data is often provided in an incremental manner. Some customer files are easier to obtain than others, such as when lengthy unarchiving processes are warranted. To ensure no time is wasted, available data can be put to use with initial analyses and model training as a Training Sample. The same data is incorporated with Training data when it is formally split into Training and Holdout sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to Students: Math is the Basis for Competitive Edge in Every Field</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_math-competitive_edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_math-competitive_edge/</guid>
      <description>Math is the greatest tool humans have for solving problems. However, it is incredibly expensive to get the experience of using it in the real-world. This is magnified by most teachers, and many university professors, not having any experience applying math anyplace other than academic contexts. This post shows the author&amp;rsquo;s trying experiences with learning maths in school, as well as the excitement of applying them to solve actual industry problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Insecurities of the &#39;Great Men&#39;</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_history-greatman_insecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_history-greatman_insecurity/</guid>
      <description>While it may be tough to find the true nature of people, past their outward appearance, it can provide insight into all people, and to yourself. The &amp;lsquo;Great Man&amp;rsquo; theory that leaders are born and not made came about in the 19th century when British aristocrats attained powerful positions through nepotism. It was primarily concerned with explaining leaders such Walpole, Wellington, and Caesar. Much of what is learned in history is their propoganda - getting the reality is much more difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>