<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cheatsheet on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/cheatsheet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cheatsheet on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/cheatsheet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Vision Using PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-pytorch_computervision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_models-pytorch_computervision/</guid>
      <description>The deep learning movement began by applying neural networks to image classification. PyTorch became a leading framework for work in this field. This post provides a cheatsheet to some of the basic methods used for computer vision, using PyTorch.
Configuration This is a typical environment setup. Seed the Random Number Generator for all devices (both CPU and CUDA) using manual_seed() so that work can be reproduced. Computations are deterministic only on your specific problem, platform, and PyTorch release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cheatsheet for Python&#39;s Pipenv</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_programming_py-pipenv_virtualenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_programming_py-pipenv_virtualenv/</guid>
      <description>Python&amp;rsquo;s Pipenv and Pyenv make a strong team for creating a consistent development environment for exact specifications. Pyenv allows you to choose from any Python version for your project. Pipenv attempts to improve upon the original virtual environment (venv) and requirements.txt file. It does some things well, including integration of virtual environment with dependecy management, and is straight-forward to use. Unfortunately, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t always live up to the originally-planned, ambitious, goals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>