<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>category2 on IMTorg Blog Site</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/category2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in category2 on IMTorg Blog Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/category2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cost of Internal Investment</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_econ-return_rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_econ-return_rate/</guid>
      <description>There is one question on every economist&amp;rsquo;s mind: Where has inflation gone? It is imperative to understanding how actors make decisions and allocate limited resources. The fact that the inflation rate is so low for so long is incredibly disconcerting for many reasons (with the fear of deflation being just one reason).
Because of low growth and a lack of inflation the US government and Federal Reserve, as well as nearly every nations&amp;rsquo; central Bank, are pouring fuel onto the economy and getting a paltry return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Command Line with Fish Shell</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_cmdln-linux_fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_cmdln-linux_fish/</guid>
      <description>The Linux terminal (typically implemented with the Bourne Again Shell Script, BASH) can be intimidating for beginners and annoying for experienced programmers. But, it is a necessity for most users of Linux; and, in many situations, it can also be a huge productivity enhancer over graphical interfaces.
Fish is a commandline tool that is a great complement to BASH. It is highly configureable and provides nice features such as syntax coloring and TAB command completion, out-of-the-box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of ToDo Posts</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_page-todo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_page-todo/</guid>
      <description> This is a list of blog posts that are referenced, but not yet complete.
List of Future Posts General Machine Learning
 scoring metrics, model performance metrics, and graphs imbalanced data feature engineering models in-depth  Natural Language Processing
 functional programming numpy nltk / spaCy gensim word2vec fasttext nlp overview  General Data Concepts
 datawarehousing infrastructure architectures serverless deployments  Business and Sales
 pricing pyramid matching problems and solutions marketing -&amp;gt; business development -&amp;gt; sales cycle and org structure  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>