<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Category on IMTorg Kbase</title>
    <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/category/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Category on IMTorg Kbase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imtorgdemo.github.io/categories/category/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple, Scalable, and Responsive Data Retrieval with ElasticSearch</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_datastore-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_datastore-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>Distributed systems are very popular tools in the &amp;lsquo;big data&amp;rsquo; market space and ElasticSearch evolved to become one of the major players. It serves the niche role of scaling to store large amounts of data, then allows querying it quickly. It evolved greatly over the last ten years to provide a variety of functionality. While it serves its primary purpose well, teams should resist the urge to use it in other roles, such as advanced analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formatting for Jupyter (.ipynb) Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_test-hugo_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_test-hugo_blog/</guid>
      <description>This is a test post for formatting Jupyter Notebooks for Hugo. This workflow makes use of the code at repository nb2hugo, as well as the beakerx jupyter kernel.
This is will test blog is a complicated workflow. Begin by running the newest version of JupyterLab. Run through the basic markdown sections. Next, try working with the R kernel by using rpy2 library. Run these cells to ensure functionality.
Then close the notebook and re-open it in Beakerx with the beakerx Groovy kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formatting a Markdown Post</title>
      <link>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_test-my_first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imtorgdemo.github.io/posts/blog_test-my_first_post/</guid>
      <description>Cupiditate voluptas sunt velit. Accusantium aliquid expedita excepturi quis laborum autem. Quas occaecati et atque est repellat dolores. Laudantium in molestiae consequatur voluptate ipsa.
Nulla quia non qui sed. Voluptatem et enim nesciunt sunt pariatur. Libero eius excepturi voluptatibus reprehenderit. Facere enim neque dolorem sed ullam non. Dolor sit molestias repellendus.
Awesome-1 Facilis maiores doloribus similique sint quaerat reiciendis quia. Autem nemo voluptas rerum. Eos odio aut omnis. Adipisci voluptas nihil autem recusandae.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>